FRONTEND DEVELOPER

amy-braswell.github.io/portfolio-site

Amy Braswell.

Profile

I am a mid-career professional seeking a frontend development position. I am a lifelong learner with 15+ years of expertise in client services, design, mentoring, production work and project delivery.

+1 773 206 5872



amy@amybraswell.com



Chicago, IL 60607



linkedin.com/amybraswell in

Skills

Languages

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript

Frameworks

- **j**Query
- React

Other

- Fetch
- Heroku
- Git / GitHub
- lest
- Enzyme
- Photoshop
- Responsive Design
- Web Accessibility

Education

MASTERS OF FINE ARTS

Photography Columbia College Chicago (3.74 / 4.00 GPA)

NURSING PREREQUISITES

Math & Sciences (40 credits) City Colleges of Chicago (3.90 / 4.00 GPA)

Volunteer

GiveCamp Memphis GiveCamp.org 2020

Projects

A CAT, A DOG, AND A TICKED OFF BIRD - A WEATHER APP

Check the Weather | See My Code

- Developed a weather app that returns the current weather conditions from three separate weather api's so the user can have a more accurate understanding of the actual weather.
- Designed the user interface for mobile and browser responsiveness.
- · Skills HTML, CSS, jQuery, Fetch, Heroku

FIND A NATIONAL PARK

Find a Park | See My Code

- Developed an app that returns the National Parks in a state the user specifies.
- Designed the user interface for mobile and browser responsiveness.
- · Skills HTML, CSS, jQuery, Fetch

CAMERA OPERATIONS QUIZ APP

Take the Quiz | See My Code

- · Developed a quiz app to test the user's understanding of camera controls.
- Designed the user interface for mobile and browser responsiveness.
- Skills HTML, CSS, ¡Query

Work Experience

APPRENTICESHIP

BLOC - WEB DEVELOPMENT FLEX TRACK | 2019 - PRESENT

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, and React.
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.
- · Upcoming lessons in Redux, Node.js, and algorithms & data structures.

Expertise

Design

- Visual Communications
- · Layout Design
- Color Theory

Business

- · Needs Analysis
- · Customer Relations
- Training & Mentoring
- Compliance

References

SHAKIR THOWSEEN

BLOC Student Advisor Thinkful sthowseen@thinkful.com

DAVID VELASQUEZ

Director of Client Services
PhotoWeb USA
719-598-4800
david.velasquez@photoweb.usa.com

REBECCA LITTLETON

Producer / Photographer
The Bellflower Collective
513-378-0110
photo@thebellflowercollective.com

Work Experience Cont.

OWNER / OPERATOR - STUDIO PHOTOGRAPHER

AMY BRASWELL PHOTOGRAPHY | 2001 - PRESENT

- Planned and prepared for all studio shoots.
- Photographed high-quality imagery for in-store, print and digital distribution.
- Collaborated with other team members to provide on-brand visuals while meeting aggressive timelines.
- Remained composed and calm in very fast-paced, stressful and constantly changing environments to provide optimal desired results.
- Developed reputation as an industry-expert through on-going research of industry trends, new techniques and software updates.

SELECT CLIENT LIST

Crate&Barrel FRONTGATE







ADJUNCT FACULTY MEMBER

PHOTOGRAPHY DEPT - COLUMBIA COLLEGE CHICAGO | 2000 - 2016

- Developed and implemented lesson plans designed to teach camera operations, tethered shooting and studio lighting.
- Engaged students by encouraging participation in class and sharing on the subject under discussion.
- Proactively mentored students in the development and achievement of their professional goals.
- Was 1 of 2 adjunct faculty members (out of 60) selected by the department to
 advise the full-time faculty on best practices in software workflow from an industry
 perspective as the department developed their digital curriculum for their core
 foundational classes.